<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on task.media Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.task.media/article/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on task.media Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-DE</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 10:30:45 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.task.media/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Control RPi GPIO throught standalone and offline WiFi (access point)</title>
      <link>https://blog.task.media/article/rpi/rpi-ap-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 10:30:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.task.media/article/rpi/rpi-ap-dns/</guid>
      <description>Background Currently I have a servo connected to my RPi which should be controlled via Smartphone. The easiest way for sure is just connect the Raspberry Pi with your home network and connect via IP address given to the RPi from your DHCP.
But in my setup this Raspberry is not always connected to the network and should be independently controllable. Therefore I needed to go for another solution.
TL;DR I created an access point on the RPi and forwarded all traffic to the local web server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup k3s with LetsEncrypt and Traefik dashboard exposed</title>
      <link>https://blog.task.media/article/k3s/k3s-letsencrypt-traefik/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.task.media/article/k3s/k3s-letsencrypt-traefik/</guid>
      <description>About This article describes how to expose a Kubernetes instance running with k3s with TLS certificates from Let’s Encrypt.
The K3s installation will install a Traefik ingress on its default configuration. But it will not have a certificate resolver present and uses the Traefik default certificate.
Versions K3s: v1.22.6+k3s1 (3228d9cb) K8s-Client: 1.23.3 K8s-Server: 1.22.6+k3s1 Traefik: 2.6.1 Traefik Helmchart: 10.9.100 Installation k3s The installation of k3s is quite simple. We are following the installation guide of k3s documentation on rancher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome back</title>
      <link>https://blog.task.media/article/welcome-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 18:53:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.task.media/article/welcome-back/</guid>
      <description>Nachdem die Website it-archiv.net in letzter Zeit nicht mehr aktiv genutzt wurde um Beiträge zu veröffentlichen, wird mit diesem Blog diese Idee fortgesetzt. Gesetzt wird wie auch schon zuvor auf Themen rund um die IT mit der Absicht eine hohe Qualität abzuliefern.
In der Kombination mit Videos (YouTube) sollen die Beiträge interaktiv gestaltet werden.
Fehler sind menschlich und sollten hier einfach behoben werden können. Aus diesem Grund wird die Homepage mit Hugo realisiert und auf github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
